(愛梨)父は 泥棒のレッテルを 貼られた自分に
耐えられなかったんだと思う｡
I don't think my dad could endure
being branded a thief.
それと 母は ホントに父が 盗んだんじゃないかと
思ってたみたい｡
And I guess my mom
did suspect that he really did it.
人を信じることを
やめたくなったよ｡➡
It made me want to stop
believing in people.
父か母の どちらかを 嫌いになれたら
気持ちが楽になるのかな って思った｡
I thought maybe I would feel better
if I could just hate
either my mom or dad.
でも ずいぶん たってから あのとき どうして
信じてあげられなかったんだろう って母が漏らしたの｡
But after years passed,
my mom let it slip,
"Why couldn't I believe him back then?"
(愛梨)そのとき 愛梨は 父も母も
好きでい続けようって思った｡
That made me want to keep
loving both of them.
(愛梨)人を信じることは
愛梨のいいところだって気付いたんだ｡
I realized that believing
in people was my strong point.
ERASED
(悟)《な… 何だ!? こりゃ》
What is this?!
(女性)さっき 愛梨ちゃんが 中に｡
I saw Airi go in there before!
ま… まだ 中にいるんじゃない？
S-She's probably still inside!
(女性)ああっ！
(女性)ちょっと！
Hey!
愛梨！
Airi!
愛梨！ 聞こえるか？
Airi! Can you hear me?!
愛梨！
Airi!
(せき)
愛梨！
Airi!
しっかりしろ！
Wake up!
《重い…》
Heavy...
おい！ 愛梨！
Hey! Airi!
くそっ！
Dammit!
《無理だ 俺の力じゃ…》
I won't make it.
I'm not strong enough.
あっ…｡
店長！
(高橋)頼りないな 漫画家ってのは｡
Manager!
Never count on a manga artist.
(高橋)
一気に下りるぞ！ 踏ん張れ！
We're goin' down, non-stop!
Brace yourself!
(高橋)悟君
君は 裏口から行け｡➡
Satoru, go out the back.
もう 愛梨君を巻き込むな｡
Don't get Airi mixed up
in your business anymore.
(高橋)手柄は 俺のもんだ｡
I'm getting the credit for this.
《愛梨は 大丈夫だろうか？》
Will Airi be okay?
《それにしても あの火事…》
And that fire...
《まさか あれも
やつの仕業だってのか？》
Don't tell me he did that too...
《そうだ》
That's right!
Sachiko Fujinuma's Phone
Incoming Mail
This is Satoru Fujinuma.
Stay right where you are.
《あの火事は 愛梨を狙った放火｡
しかも その犯人は俺だ》
The fire was set to target Airi.
And it looks like I did it!
つまり このメールを 警察に 見られないようにするために➡ 愛梨は…｡
Airi slipped the phone to me
so the police couldn't see this message.
やつは もともと
愛梨の家を知っていたか➡
Then he knew from the beginning
where Airi lived.
愛梨をつけた…》
He followed her.
《思っているより 近い所に
やつは いるのかも》
He may be closer than I think.
《捜すんだ！ 俺が捕まるのが先か
やつを見つけ出すのが先か》
I'll look for him.
Either I get caught first
or I find him first.
Koiwa. Koiwa.
[ﾏｲｸ](車掌)小岩｡ 小岩です｡
車内に お忘れ物…｡
Please do not leave
any articles on the train...
COLUMBUS RECORDS
[TEL]
(澤田)はい｡➡
Yes?
誰？ いいかげんに名乗ったら？
Who is this?
Why don't you just
identify yourself already?
[TEL]藤沼 悟です｡
It's Satoru Fujinuma.
(澤田)あんたが 藤沼 悟さんなら
初めまして｡➡
If you are Satoru Fujinuma,
nice to meet you.
お電話 お待ちしておりました｡➡
I've been waiting for your call.
ええ ぜひ｡➡
Yes, by all means.
ああ ここは 駄目ですよ｡
外で会いましょう｡➡
No, not here.
Let's meet at a public place.
ああ 僕 まだ 名乗ってませんね｡
あした お会いしたときに｡➡
I haven't given you
my name yet, have I?
I will when we meet tomorrow.
あなたが 藤沼 佐知子殺害の
犯人かもしれないからですよ｡
Because you may have
murdered Sachiko Fujinuma.
KOHAKUTEI COFFEE SHOP
≪(店員)いらっしゃいませ｡
Welcome.
(澤田)
やあ 悟君｡ こっち こっち｡➡
Hi, Satoru. Over here.
初めまして｡
元 テレビ石狩 社会部の澤田です｡
Good to meet you.
I'm Sawada, formerly of TV Ishikari.
よかった｡
ホントに 悟君だった｡➡
I'm relieved. You really are Satoru.
うん｡ お母さんの面影あるよ｡
Yeah, you resemble your mother.
《あっ…｡ あの人だ》
Him!
警戒してきただろうけど
通報もしてないし➡
I'm sure you're on guard, but I didn't
tell anyone about this meeting,
僕の方も
君のお母さんを殺していない｡
and I didn't murder
your mother either.
僕を疑ってないんですか？
もちろん｡
You don't suspect me?
Of course not.
どうして？
Why not?
あの人は 自分を殺すような息子を
育てないからさ｡
Because she didn't raise
the kind of son who would kill her.
(澤田)なるほどね｡
I see.
昨日 ポケットに入っていたのを
思い出しました｡
Yesterday I remembered
that it was in my pocket.
大変なことになってしまったね｡
情けないです｡
This keeps snowballing.
I'm pathetic.
連続で 下手をうってしまった
自分の責任もあります｡
My string of blunders
makes me partially responsible.
自分のせいなんて思うのは
思い上がりってもんだべさ｡
Thinking it's your fault
after the fact is just pointless.
ハッ…｡
佐知子さんの言葉だけどな｡
僕の好きな言葉なんだ｡
Those are Sachiko's words.
I always liked them.
佐知子さんからの電話の話を
しようか｡
Shall we talk about her phone call?
お願いします｡
Please.
COIN LAUNDRY
[TEL](佐知子)《澤田君 覚えてる？
18年前の連続殺人事件》
Sawada, do you remember?
The serial killings 18 years ago...
《もちろん》
Of course.
《白鳥 潤死刑囚は
いまだ 犯行を認めていないよ》
Jun Shiratori is on death row,
but he still claims to be innocent.
[TEL](佐知子)《あれ
悟の言ったとおりだったわ》
It's just as Satoru said.
《えっ？》
[TEL](佐知子)
《犯人は 白鳥君じゃない》➡
Shiratori didn't do it.
《真犯人 誰だか分かっちゃった｡
じゃあ あした 小岩駅で》
Now I know who did.
Let's meet at Koiwa Station tomorrow.
(澤田)
名前まで聞いておくんだったよ｡
I should've asked her for the name.
一つ 昔の話をしようか｡
Why don't we talk about a past incident?
雛月 加代ちゃんの事件だ｡
About Kayo Hinazuki's death...
(澤田)昭和63年 ３月２日 夜｡➡
On the night of March 2nd, 1988,
加代は 母と その彼氏から
暴行を受け➡ 物置に閉じ込められた｡➡
Kayo was beaten by her mother
and her mother's boyfriend,
and locked in the storage shed.
彼女は そのまま 凍死｡
死体を隠蔽したと考えて➡
She froze to death.
The police suspected Kayo's mother
and the boyfriend of hiding the body.
警察は 一度
加代の母と男に 容疑をかける｡➡
だが 実際は２日 22時から23時の間に
加代は 物置から失踪していた｡
But sometime between 10
and 11 pm on the 2nd,
Kayo disappeared from the shed.
３日 ０時30分に 失踪に気付いた加代の母は
藤沼家に電話をして さりげなく 行方を捜していた｡
Kayo's mother discovered
the disappearance at 12:30 am on the 3rd.
She called your house and casually
inquired about Kayo's whereabouts.
証拠の一つは➡連れ去ったのは 白鳥 潤｡
Jun Shiratori had taken her away.
物置の周囲に残っていた ゴム長靴の足跡が
白鳥家のものと 一致したこと｡
The footprints made
by rubber boots around the shed
matched Jun Shiratori's boots.
HOKKAIDO POLICE
警察が公表している犯行手口は
暴行を加えて 気絶させ 写真撮影を行う｡➡
The police went public
with their version of the events.
Shiratori knocked Kayo out
with physical violence
and then photographed her.
業務用冷凍庫内にて 霧吹きを使い
急速に凍死させる｡➡
He put her in the family
business cold storage room
and used an atomizer
to speed up her death by freezing.
体温が 20度に下がった時点で
脳死｡➡
When her temperature dropped
to 20 degrees, she was brain dead.
蘇生の可能性が ほぼ
なくなるまで 30分ほど待ち➡
Shiratori waited about 30 minutes,
when she had almost
zero chance of recovery,
日の出前に
雛月家物置に 凍死体を戻した｡
then returned her frozen corpse
to the Hinazuki shed before sunrise.
ユウキさんが
そんなこと するわけない！
Yuuki would never have done that!
雛月 加代｡ 杉田 広美｡ 中西 彩｡
Kayo Hinazuki, Hiromi Sugita,
Aya Nakanishi...
３人の事件の少し前
Shortly before those three disappeared,
隣の市でも誘拐殺人事件が
起きているんだが➡
there was a series of abduction
murders in the next town over.
犯人は スピード逮捕され
白鳥 潤と同じく 犯行を全面否認｡
The culprit was quickly arrested,
but like Jun Shiratori,
he denied any wrongdoing.
さて 君の今の状況を含めて
何か 気付かないかい？
Now.
Including your present circumstances,
do you notice a common link?
あっ｡ 解決済みの事件を調べる➡ 変な
ルポライター｡ 散々 笑われてきたけどね｡
I've been ridiculed for years for being
a weirdo freelancer reporter
who investigates crimes
that have already been solved.
実は 一つも解決していない｡
The truth is, none of them are solved!
雛月 加代も 佐知子さんも➡
Both Kayo Hinazuki and Sachiko
were murdered by the same bastard
別の犯人を用意する
同じやつに殺された！
who gives the police another suspect!
そいつが 今 この街に…｡
相当 狡猾なやつだよ｡
And now he's in this city.
He's a crafty son of a bitch.
別の容疑者を用意して 時間を稼ぐことで➡
目撃証言も減り 現場の状況も変わっていく｡
He buys time by framing someone else,
which reduces eyewitness testimony
and changes the circumstances
at the scene.
自分から 捜査が
どんどん遠ざかっていくわけだ｡
As a result, the investigation gets
further and further away from himself.
(愛梨)フーッ｡
《大げさだなぁ》
This is going overboard.
(刑事)口封じの線か｡
So he tried to shut her up.
(刑事)藤沼 悟…｡ この状態なら
手出しは 不可能だな｡
Satoru Fujinuma...
He won't be able to get at her now.
(刑事)それより 女子高生の方だ｡
(刑事)共犯か…｡
And what about the high school girl?
Is she an accomplice?
(刑事)母親殺しに協力させて
用済みになったら 口封じか…｡
She helped him kill the mother
and once that was done,
he tried to silence her.
(刑事)ひでえ話だな
あんな娘を巻き込むとは｡
That's terrible.
Getting that girl caught up
in his madness...
(愛梨)《違う…》
You're wrong.
(愛梨のおじ)《愛梨ちゃん君が謝ることはないんだ
(愛梨のおば)《そうよ》
Airi, you have nothing to apologize for.
That's right. A stalker went after you.
《あんなストーカーに
狙われていたなんて➡
怖かったでしょう？》
You must have been terrified!
(愛梨)
《おばさん そうじゃないの》
Aunty, that's not what happened.
(愛梨のおば)《いいのよ｡ 気付いてあげられなくて
ごめんなさい》
Don't blame yourself. I'm sorry
that we didn't notice anything.
(愛梨)《違う…》
It's not what you think.
(愛梨のおじ)《犯人の男は
警察が追っている》
The police are after the culprit.
《怖がることは ないんだよ》
You have nothing to be afraid of now.
(愛梨)《違うのに…》
They've got it wrong.
Fugitive Suspect
Responsible for Arson?
Suspect Targeted
Co-worker's House (Chiba)
(愛梨)《悟さんが殺人や放火で追われるなんて
あり得ない…》
I can't believe they're going
after Satoru for murder and arson.
That's impossible...
《誰なら 信じてくれるの？》
Who would believe me...
(澤田)佐知子さんの携帯から
メールが その子に？
A message was sent
from Sachiko's phone to that girl?
はい｡ 報道では 軽傷と言ってましたが➡
今は まだ 病院でしょう｡
Yes.
According to the news,
she wasn't badly hurt,
but I'm sure she's still in the hospital.
これです｡
This is it.
なるほど｡ 君に 放火の容疑をかぶせて捜査の促進を図った｡
I see.
He plotted to help the investigation along
by framing you for arson.
それもあると思いますが
もう すでに 僕は容疑者なんです｡
I think that's part of it,
but I was already a suspect.
彼女… 片桐 愛梨といいますが
それだけが理由で 狙ったとは思えない｡
I can't believe he would target her,
Airi Katagiri, just for that.
つまり その子自身も
やつのターゲットだと？
In other words, you think
she was already his target?
やつは 僕を 母さん殺しの犯人に 仕立てるために
バイト先からの帰宅時間を 知る必要があった｡
In order to frame me
as my mother's murderer,
he had to find out what time
I'd be home from my job.
つまり 母さんに 誘拐未遂を目撃されてから 殺すまでの一日と少しの間に
やつは あの店に来て シフト表を見ているんです｡
So in the 24 hours plus
between my mother's sighting
of his attempted
kidnapping and her murder,
he went to the pizza shop
and looked at the shift schedule.
そして そのとき
愛梨に 顔を見られた｡
Airi must have seen his face then.
もしかしたら
僕も知っている人間かも…｡
Maybe he's even someone I know.
なるほど｡ シフト表のある店内に
入りこむことのできる人間 ということか｡
I see. Then he's someone
who could get behind the counter
at a pizza shop to look at the schedule.
これは ひょっとすると
犯人に 手が届くかもしれないぞ｡
We may be able to use
this to reach the bad guy.
ちょっと 病院へ行ってくるよ｡
えっ？ はい｡
I'm going to the hospital.
Okay.
パソコンに
18年前の事件のリポートがある｡
There's a report on the murders
from 18 years ago on my computer.
見てていいよ｡
You can take a look if you like.
(澤田)｢白鳥 潤は 自分の父親が
犯人だと思っているのではないか｣
I think Jun Shiratori suspects
his own father of being the killer.
(澤田)｢アリバイ 物証に関して
父親に不利な面で 黙秘し続けたことが
Regarding an alibi and evidence,
it's possible that his continued
refusal to say anything
より 印象を
悪くしたと考えられる｣
that might incriminate his father
made himself look even worse.
《父親思いの
ユウキさんらしいや》
That would be like Yuuki,
who dearly loves his father.
(澤田)｢雛月 加代と白鳥 潤が 一緒に居る所を➡
同級生が 再三 目撃している｣➡
A classmate saw Kayo Hinazuki
and Jun Shiratori together three times.
｢藤沼 悟の証言は 黙殺されたが➡
こちらの証言は 大きく参考にされた模様｣
Satoru Fujinuma's testimony
was deliberately ignored,
but it seems much was made
of the other student's testimony.
あっ｡
《容疑者リストだ》
FINAL SUSPECT LIST
Jun Shiratori
Seiichiro Shiratori
Isao Ishidou
Shinji Sakashita
Tadashi Yanagida
A list of suspects.
《ユウキさん親子以外は
知らない名前…》
I don't know any of these names
other than Yuuki and his father.
《しかも たった５人》
And there are only five?
(澤田)｢警察の推測では➡ 杉田 広美は
女児と間違われて 殺害されたものとされている｣➡
The police guessed
that Hiromi Sugita was murdered
after being mistaken for a girl.
｢これにより 杉田 広美と面識のない５名が➡
最終的な容疑者リストに残った｣
From this, the police made up
a final list of five suspects
who weren't acquainted
with Hiromi Sugita.
(ヒロミ)
《今日 フォークダンスだって》
We're doing folk dancing today.
Ice Hockey Club
1988 National Champions
(カズ)《え～っ マジかよ！》
Seriously?!
(オサム)
《ブスと 手つなぐの やだな》➡
I don't wanna hold hands
with some ugly girl.
《ヒロミの方が 全然いいべ！》
(ヒロミ)《だ… 大胆！》
I'd much rather hold hands
with you, Hiromi!
T-That's gutsy!
《ヒロミが殺された理由が
分かった》
I know why Hiromi was murdered.
《犯人は 男だと知っていて自分を 容疑者リストから
外すためだけに あえて ヒロミを殺したんだ
He knew Hiromi was a boy,
so he killed him to keep himself
off the list of suspects.
(澤田)｢同市内の小学３年生女児が 一人でいるところに声を掛けた白鳥
潤が 近隣住民の通報により 逮捕された｣
Jun Shiratori was arrested after someone
in the neighborhood reported
that he'd been talking
to a third-grade girl when she was alone.
｢杉田 広美殺害時に 撮影された写真が白鳥食品の倉庫から押収され
これにより 白鳥 潤は小児性愛の傾向にあると 結論づけられた｣
Photos taken at the time
of Hiromi Sugita's death
were confiscated from Shiratori's
food storage room.
The police concluded that Jun Shiratori
had pedophiliac tendencies.
｢さらに 自室からは➡ 小児性愛関連の書籍も 押収されており…｣
They also collected pedophilia-related
publications from his bedroom.
《そんな物 なかった！》
That kind of stuff wasn't there!
Perfect Day for Pleasure
Perfect Day for All You Can See
Strawberry: Beautiful Girl Photo Album
High School Girls' Uniform Reference Guide
Erotica
Paper Craft
《全て やつが 自分から 目を
そらすために仕組んだ偽装だ》
It's all camouflage to draw
attention away from himself!
ヒロミが死ぬ前の容疑者リスト…｡
The list of suspects
before Hiromi's death...
Previous Suspect List
《この中に やつの名前がある》
His name is on here!
≪(ノック)
≪(看護師)片桐さん 入るよ｡
Ms. Katagiri, I'm coming in.
2F NURSES STATION
(澤田)あの…
見舞いだけど トイレは あっち？
Excuse me...
I'm here to visit,
but is the restroom over there?
Yes.
(看護師)はい｡
(澤田)《満床…｡
で 201号のみ 空き》
No vacancies...
except for room 201.
(看護師)眠ってますよ｡
(刑事)そうですか｡
She's sleeping.
Is that right?
(澤田)ヤバい！ 漏れる 漏れる！
Crap! I'm gonna spring a leak!
(澤田)ぶしつけで すみません
片桐 愛梨さん｡
Please pardon my
bad manners, Airi Katagiri.
≪藤沼 悟さんじゃないみたいね｡
You're not Satoru Fujinuma, are you?
(澤田)えっ？ あっ はい｡➡
Right. I'm his friend, Sawada.
その友人の澤田と申します｡
(愛梨の母)
初めまして｡ 愛梨の母です｡
Nice to meet you.
I'm Airi's mother.
Episode 6
Grim Reaper
(愛梨)
《悟さんは 絶対やってないの》➡
I'm positive Satoru didn't do any of it.
《お母さんも殺してない｡
愛梨を狙った放火もしてない》➡
He didn't kill his mother.
And he didn't set a fire to target me!
《火事のとき 悟さんは
愛梨を助けに来たんだよ》
During the fire, he came
to the house to rescue me!
《君を助けたのは
店長さんでしょ？》
Your manager saved you, right?
《煙
いっぱい吸っちゃったからね》
You must be confused
after inhaling all that smoke.
《お母さんは 何て聞いてるか知らないけど
愛梨は 共犯者かもって思われてるよ》
I don't know
what they're asking you, Mom,
but they think I may be an accomplice!
《信じてもらえないのって
半端なく つらいよ》➡
Not being believed
is what hurts the most.
《誰が 悟さんのこと➡ 信じてくれるんだろう って考えたら…》
When I think
about who believes in Satoru...
(愛梨の母)《愛梨｡ お母さんも➡
追い掛ければよかったって 今でも思ってるの》
Airi...
Even now, I think
I should've gone after him.
《いってらっしゃい｡
大丈夫｡ 愛梨を信じてる》
Go ahead.
It's all right.
I believe you, Airi.
[TEL]
うん？
《しまった…｡
電源 切るの忘れてた》
Shoot!
I forgot to turn it off.
[TEL]
Public Phone
[TEL](愛梨)
よかった！ 電源 入ってた！
Thank goodness! You had it on!
愛梨か!? 大丈夫なのか？
Airi?
Are you okay?
[TEL]うん｡
もう ぴんぴんしてるよ｡➡
Yeah. I'm as good as new.
それよりさ 今から会える？
例の場所で｡
More importantly, can I see you?
At the usual place...
えっ？ 駄目だ！ 来るな！
そんなことしたら 愛梨まで…｡
What? No, stay away from there!
Airi, I can't have you—
It's all right! I promise, I'll go alone!
[TEL]大丈夫！
絶対 一人で行くから！
[TEL](通話の切れる音)
あっ…｡
(男の子)いっけ～！
(男の子)飛ぶのかよ!?
Go! It's flying!
《のこのこ やって来ちまった》
And here I am...
《真犯人のことなら
電話でだって 話せた》
She may have been speaking
to the real killer on the phone.
《巻き込んじまったら 愛梨の
立場が悪くなるだけなのに…》
Getting Airi involved
will only make it worse for her.
SHINJI
(男の子)何だよ｡
What the heck?!
全然 飛ばねえじゃん｡
(男の子)おかしいな｡ 何でだろ｡
That's not flying at all!
Strange...
I don't know why...
こうしてさ
揚力ってのをつけてやるんだ｡
Doing this gives it
what's called dynamic lift.
ホントに これで飛ぶようになる？
なるさ｡
Will it really fly now?
It sure will.
やーっ！
あっ！ ホントだ！ すげえ！
It's true! Awesome!
わあ！ 川の方 行ったぞ｡
It went by the river!
(男の子)わあ！ 飛び過ぎ！
That's flyin' too far! Cool!
What's an adult doing here
at this time of day?
(女性)ねえ ちょっと あの人…｡
(女性)仕事してないのかしら｡
Good question...
《ユウキさんも
こんな感じの思い してたのかな》
Is this how people thought of Yuuki?
(愛梨)ハァ… ハァ…｡
ハァ…｡ あっ｡
あっ｡
来たよ 悟さん｡
うん｡
I'm here, Satoru.
Yeah.
約束どおり 一人で来たよ｡
うん｡
As promised, I came alone.
Yeah.
警察の わなの可能性まで考えた
自分が 恥ずかしい｡
I'm ashamed for thinking
it might be a police trap.
《声に出てた…》
I said that out loud!
ハハハッ！
そのくらいじゃないと駄目だよ｡
You better think that way!
悟さんは 逃亡者なんだから｡
You're a fugitive, Satoru.
でも
愛梨を信じてくれて うれしいよ｡
But I'm glad you trust me.
うん｡
Yeah.
(愛梨)お店に？
The shop?
西園って人が 怪しいと思う｡
西園？
I think this Nishizono guy is fishy.
Nishizono?
二～三度 見掛けたよ｡
店長が 先生って呼んでたし➡
I've seen him two or three times.
The manager treats him with respect
バッジ 着けてたから
たぶん 市会議員｡
and from the badge he wears,
I'd guess he's a city councilman.
そいつなら
シフト表も見られたはずだし➡
He would've been able
to see the schedule,
愛梨たちの家 分かっても
おかしくない｡
and it's not unlikely
that he knew where I lived.
挨拶したこともあるよ｡
I've met him before, briefly.
《西園？
リストには なかったぞ》
PREVIOUS SUSPECT LIST
Jun Shiratori
Seiichiro Shiratori
Isao Ishidou
Shinji Sakashita
Makoto Kawata
Sachiko Fujinuma
Nishizono?
He wasn't on the list.
《偽名？ しかし
市議で 偽名は使えないはず》
A fake name?
But a city council member
wouldn't be able to use a fake name.
顔 知ってたから
愛梨は 狙われたんだと思う｡
I think he targeted me
because I know his face.
《くそっ！ つながんねえ！
最後のピースが はまらねえ！》
Dammit! It isn't coming together.
The final piece won't fit!
悟さん… 気持ちは分かるけど
無茶しちゃ駄目だよ｡
Satoru...
I know how you feel,
but you can't beat yourself up over it.
ずっと昔に
やり残したことがあるんだ｡
I have unfinished business
from a long time ago.
えっ？
あっ いや 俺が考えた漫画の話｡
It's an idea I had for a manga story.
予定を間違えて 子供を
死なせてしまった死神の話だ｡
About a grim reaper
who makes a scheduling mistake
that results in the death of a child.
何とか 元に戻そうとして
あがいて➡
He struggles to put things
back the way they were,
動けば動くほど
関わる人たちが不幸になっていく｡
but the more he acts, the more
other people involved suffer.
正しいことを しているつもりなのに➡
自分が関わってしまうと 他人が傷ついてしまう…｡
Even though he means
to do the right thing,
when he gets mixed up in it,
other people get hurt.
(愛梨)
それが 今の悟さんみたいだって？
It's like you right now, Satoru?
愛梨も そう思わないか？
バカなの？
Don't you think, Airi?
Are you stupid?
えっ？
愛梨 傷ついてないし｡
For example, I'm not hurt.
他人が どうとかは
死神の思い込みだよ｡
That stuff about other people is just
the reaper's subjective impression.
その死神は
もっと 自分を信じていいと思う｡
I think that grim reaper
should have more faith in himself.
今 目の前にあるのは
きっと 全部 途中経過だよ｡
I'm sure that what's in front of you
is all still in progress.
結末は もっと先のことで
まだ 誰にも分からないんだから｡
The conclusion is still up ahead
and nobody knows what it is yet.
愛梨
本当に 君に会えてよかった｡
Airi, I'm really glad that we met today.
えっ!?
《声に出てた…》
I said that out loud!
(刑事)藤沼 悟だな？
Satoru Fujinuma, I presume?
悟さん！
(刑事)邪魔をするな！
Satoru!
Don't interfere!
(愛梨)ああっ！
愛梨！
Airi!
(刑事)藤沼 悟｡殺人および
放火殺人未遂の容疑で逮捕する｡
Satoru Fujinuma,
you're under arrest for murder
and attemped murder resulting from arson.
(警察官)16時50分 被疑者 確保｡
The suspect was apprehended at 4:50 pm.
CHIBA POLICE
(愛梨)どうしてなの!?
悟さんは やってないよ！➡
Why?!
Satoru didn't do it!
やるわけないじゃん！
悟さん！
He would never do it!
Satoru!
《愛梨との関係は逮捕か リバイバルのいずれかで
消滅するのは 覚悟していた》
Either through being arrested or Revival,
I was prepared to have my
relationship with Airi disappear.
《そして 今が
愛梨との最後の時だ》
And here it is, the last time I'll see her.
《俺が 今すべきことは…》
The thing I should do right now is...
悟さん！ ごめんなさい！
Satoru!
I'm sorry!
きっと この人たち
私が 連れてきちゃった！
I bet they followed me here!
一人で来るって 約束したのに…｡
Even though I promised
I'd come alone!
《俺が 愛梨に与えたかったものを
与えるんだ》
I have to give Airi
what I wanted to give her.
《愛梨が
俺に そうしてくれたように》
Just like she did for me.
ごめんなさい！ ごめんなさい！
ごめんなさい… 私のせいだ｡
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
I'm sorry...
It's my fault!
《こんなとき
ヒーローなら 何て言うかな》
What would a hero say at a time like this?
(悟)《独りぼっちで戦うのって
つらくないの？》
Isn't it hard fighting all on your own?
愛梨 違うよ｡
Airi, you've got it wrong.
君が信じてくれたから
俺は… まだ頑張れる｡
I can still hang in there
because you believed in me.
ありがとう 愛梨｡
君を信じてよかった｡
Thank you, Airi.
I'm glad I trusted you.